Ryan Williams

Software Engineer

RyanMichaelWilliams@gmail.com | ryanwilliams.io

Summary

I'm an end-to-end Software Engineer with industry experience in E-commerce and Marketing companies, specializing in Microsoft technologies using Windows Azure. I work on Continuous Deployment, API development and testing. I have worked in startup, mid-size and international corporate organizations in both contract and full-time roles. I enjoy working on projects that make an impact in the world, with a motivated team or independently.

Recent Experience

Senior Software Engineer at Link Launcher (San Francisco, CA) – linklauncher.com

November 2016 - Present

Designed and developed custom Affiliate Marketing Network which runs in Windows Azure. It utilizes queues, continuous deployment and bank transfers using Stripe's API, all written in C#. Open source work on Stripe's official C# SDK was done too. Website offers various reports and tools for affiliates and advertisers to grow their businesses using a portal an API.

Lead Software Engineer at Rakuten/ Rakuten Marketing (San Francisco, CA) - rakuten.com

January 2013 - October 2016

Worked with Windows Azure, C#, ASP.NET (MVC), Entity Framework, PowerShell, HTML/ CSS/ JavaScript, Git, TeamCity/ Bamboo, AWS and SQL to deliver high availability, cloud-based REST APIs. Developed APIs for desktop and mobile clients in an Agile environment. Created Unit, Integration and Performance tests. Developed task driven Continuous Integration/ Deployment scripts used to release applications. Worked in FinTech space with payment processors, assisted with Bitcoin integration in Japan and the USA. Contributed to open source on GitHub, attended industry conferences, hackathons and investor meetings.

Technical Lead Developer at LyntonWeb (San Francisco, CA) - <u>lyntonweb.com</u>

January 2012 - August 2012

Contracted to lead a team that built an intranet site for content ranking and employee evaluation. Project was conducted remotely. Technologies included: HTML/ CSS/ JavaScript, TeamCity, Mercurial, Fluent Nhibernate, ASP.NET, SQL Server 2008, AWS and C#. The application was internationalized to accommodate multiple languages.

Software Engineer at Jar Media (San Francisco, CA) - jarmedia.com

June 2009 - September 2011

Primary developer at affiliate marketing start-up. Met with business owners and affiliate partners to create a high traffic custom CMS pages that worked with many custom credit card processor integrations. Processed large volume of credit cards, interfaced with CRM systems that did rebilling securely. Worked on optimizing, scaling and designing pages used by super affiliates. Technologies included: ASP.NET, C#, SQL Server, Windows Server, AWS, Cisco Firewall and external load testing frameworks.

Web Developer at Pioneer Technology Group (Orlando, FL) - ptghome.com

August 2008 - February 2009

Built a web portal in ASP.NET using Visual Basic and SQL Server for the real estate industry which managed digitized title documents for home owners. Additionally, worked on and released an application to county government servers that managed tourist tax revenue.

Education

- BSBA, Management of Information Systems University of Central Florida 2007
- BSBA, Marketing University of Central Florida 2007